The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
Bastard!
貴様
That's as far as you're going to get.
これ以上はやらせんよ
Dad!
父さん
He was trying to make philosopher's stones again.
こいつ　また賢者の石を作ろうとしていた
Humans should just stay as stones.
人間はおとなしく石になっておればいい
Why do you treat humans like such lowly creatures?
なんでそんなに下等生物扱いするかねぇ
人間からは賢者の石が出来る
Philosopher's stones can be created from humans,
賢者の石からは人造人間が出来る
and homunculi can be created from philosopher's stones.
So, answer me. What can be created from homunculi?
では　人造人間からは
何が出来る　何を生む
What do you give birth to?!
An existence that only brings about destruction can be called 'God'?
破壊しかもたらさぬ存在を神と呼べるのか
You may believe that you've become a perfect being,
完全な存在になったつもりだろうが
but all you are is an obstacle in the cycle of life!
どん詰まりなんだよ　お前は
Is that so?
そうかね　ならば　人間を生もう
Then I shall give birth to humans.
I've obtained immortality....
不老不死を手に入れた…
私はまだ生きている…
I'm still alive...
King Xerxes!
クセルクセス王
体だ
A body!
This body is mine!
体を手に入れた
やっと体を…
Finally, a body...
やめろ やめてくれ
Stop...
Please, stop...
This... This isn't right!
こんなの…こんなの違う
Look! A body!
見ろ　肉体だ
Hohenheim...
ホーエンハイム…
みんな…
Guys...
You!!
貴様
Shoot!
なんだ　何が起こってる
What the hell is going on?!
Shit!
くそっ
Greed!
グリード
D.K.!
ゴリウス
無事だったか
Looks like you're okay.
Great timing! Give me a ride.
ちょうどいい　オレも乗せてけ
It'll probably help to have someone with you who knows what's up.
状況分かってるヤツが必要だろ
そうだ
Yeah! What on earth is going on?!
一体何が起こってるんだ
The leader of the homunculi, "Father," is off on a rampage.
お父様っつう
親玉人造人間が暴れてんだよ
Those who can't fight should get off right here!
こっから先　戦えねぇヤツは置いてけ
おら　そこのカエルと女２人降りろ
Hey!
The frog and the two princesses!
Scram!
ケガしてんだろ
You're all injured!
Don't be ridiculous!
バカを言うな
Who else but me will take the lead?!
私が隊を指揮せんで　誰がする
知ったことか　さっさと降りろ
Hell if I know!
Just get the hell off of there!
指揮とかなんとか
This ain't the time to be blabbering on about leading!
言ってる場合じゃねぇんだよ
貴様に指図される…
You have no right to-
閣下
General!
本部から通信です
A call from headquarters.
作戦本部　私だ
Mission headquarters? It's me.
What's the status over there?
そっちはどうなっている
閣下　中央司令部が…
Ma'am, half of Central Headquarters...
...has been annihilated.
半分吹っ飛びました
What?
なんと…
北門と連絡がつきません
We can't get in touch with the North Gate.
That's what he's capable of.
それがヤツの力だ
一体　そいつは…
Just what is he...?
He looks like an ordinary human from the outside.
見た目は普通の人間だ
ただし　ウン十万人分の賢者の石を
However, he has several hundred thousand human souls worth of philosopher's stones stored in his body,
体内に持っていて
and has absorbed God with that energy.
そのエネルギーで
神の力とやらを取り込んでいる
錬金術師なら　このヤバさが分かるだろ
You alchemists out there should understand the severity of the situation.
Philosopher's stones...
賢者の石…
You ordinary humans should stay behind.
普通の人間はここで降りな
My men are up there fighting.
私の部下が上でまだ戦っている
I am their commander.
私は彼らの指揮官なのだ
General, headquarters would like to speak with you.
閣下　本部が代わってほしいと
What is it?
なんだ
Don't worry, General.
ご心配なく　閣下
Don't forget that we Briggs soldiers are capable of operating even if our boss is absent.
我々ブリッグズ兵はボスが不在でも
ひるまず動くことができる
軍隊だということをお忘れですか
Armory, Team Yellow! Are you alive?!
武器庫　イエロー隊　生きてるか
東門　ブルー隊　応答せよ
East Gate, Team Blue! Come in!
聞けば　ケガをしているそうではありませんか
We overheard that you're injured.
Please watch over us from there.
どうぞそこで見守っていてください
Alex!
アレックス
はいっ
Ma'am!
Bring the communications equipment!
通信機を持っていけ
Win no matter what!
必ず勝て
Of course we will!
言われずとも
よし　行くぞ　中尉
Right. Let's go, Lieutenant.
Hey! Both of you are hurt!
２人ともケガ人だろうが
ヤツの賢者の石を私が焼き尽くす
I'll burn his philosopher's stone to a crisp.
But in order for me to do that, I'll need the lieutenant's help.
そのためには中尉の助けが必要だ
いいから　早く行こうぜ
Who cares, let's get a move on.
私の仕事は若をお守りすることだ
My duty is to protect the young master.
Please take care of Izumi...
イズミを…みんなを頼む
...and everyone else.
Let's rock 'n' roll!!
それではいきますぞぉ
So this is where he bit the dust.
こんな所で死んだか
Did you do this?
貴様が倒したのか
He was heavily injured by the time he got here.
ここに来たときすでに満身創痍だった
If that hadn't been the case, I'm not sure whether I would have made it out alive.
そうでなければ　オレも危なかった
バッカニア大尉はシン国の者と協力し
Captain Buccaneer dealt a fatal blow to Bradley with the aid of a man from Xing...
ブラッドレイに致命傷を与え…
どうだ　ブラッドレイ
So, Bradley...
...wouldn't you say my men were quite something?
私の部下は強かったろう
Shao May, you're all right...
シャオメイ
無事だったのね…よかった…
Thank goodness...
Sir Alphonse?!
アルフォンス様
May...
メイ…よかった　生きてた
I'm glad you're alive...
Sir Alphonse, your body...!
アルフォンス様　体が…
Sir Alphonse!
アルフォンス様
Oh no! If you hadn't protected me...!
そんな…私をかばって…
アルフォンス様…
Sir Alphonse!
Sir Alphonse!!
アルフォンス様
Master!
師匠
Master! Master!!
師匠 師匠
I'm still alive...
生きてるよ…
Mr. Hohenheim protected us...
ホーエンハイムさんが
ギリギリ守ってくれた…
H-Hohenheim!
ホ…ホーエンハイム
Hey! Hang in there!
しっかりしろ
Hohenheim!!
ホーエンハイム
Two to start with.
まず２つ
や…やめろ
Stop it!!
Our target is a man with long, blonde hair!
目標は金髪長髪の男
Don't confuse him with the Fullmetal Alchemist!
鋼の錬金術師と間違えるなよ
Roger!
東門　ブルー隊　急げ
East Gate, Team Blue! Step on it!
West Gate, Team White! Get in the shadows of the west building of headquarters!
西門　ホワイト隊は司令部西棟の陰に
了解
Yes, sir!
Master!
師匠
Fire!!
撃て
Yo, Fullmetal! You alive?
鋼の　無事か
Attacks like these won't even scratch him!
ダメだ　これぐらいじゃ
ビクともしないぞ
うそだろ
You're kidding me!
Don't give him a chance to counterattack!
ヤツに反撃の隙を与えるな
Aye, sir!
アイ　サー
Dammit! He looks like he's enjoying the breeze!
くそっ　涼しい顔してやがる
Roger that!
了解　各隊へつなげ
Put me through to each squadron.
本当ですか
Is that so?!
Cease fire! Duck!
攻撃やめ　伏せろ
当たったか
Did I hit him?
わずかにそれました
Grazed him.
１２時の方向に修正
Fix your aim towards 12 o'clock.
目が見えんから火加減が分からん
I can't see, so I don't know how much I should suppress my flames.
加減する必要はありません
Don't suppress them at all!
距離５０…いえ　５３
Distance 50...
No, 53!
どうも　この手合わせ錬成は
I still can't get used to this clapping business.
しっくりこん
正面　攻撃　来ます
A frontal attack!
お見事
Nice work!
Take that back. It's pretty useful.
こいつは便利だな
撃て撃て　撃ちまくれ
Fire! Fire!
Keep it up!
反撃の隙を与えるな
Don't give him the chance to counterattack!
ヤツに賢者の石を使わせ続けろ
Keep making him use up his philosopher's stone!
すげぇ
Incredible!
あの力がありゃ
I could make the world mine if I had that power!
世界は全部オレのものにできるぜ
Hey, Greed!
グリード
貴様の言ってた
Is this what you meant by "making the world yours"?
世界を手に入れるってのは
こういうことだったのか
That's right!
あれを手に入れれば
If I could just obtain that, the entire world would be mine!
世の中は全部オレのものだ
オレの中の空っぽが
This feeling of emptiness inside me might just be cured!
これで埋まるかもしれねぇ
生まれてから
The thirst that's been haunting me since birth just might be quenched!
ずっと続いてきた渇きが
治まるかもしれねぇ
あさましいな  グリード
You're disgraceful, Greed.
お前が欲しいものは
That's not what you really want.
それじゃないはずだ
黙ってろ　しょんべんガキが
Keep your mouth shut, shitty brat!
オレは強欲のグリードだ
I'm Greed, the avaricious!
欲しいものは必ず手に入れる
I'll obtain everything I want at any cost!
Homunculus Cake, anyone?
蒸し焼きだ
まったく効かん
Not even a scratch...
あの防壁をなんとかせねば…
We need to do something about that barrier!
弾が足りん　もっと持ってこい
We're running out of ammo! Bring us some more!
無駄なことを　人間ごときは
Futile acts.
Mere humans can hardly lay a finger on me.
私に指一本触れることはできん
人間がダメなら
If humans can't, what about a homunculus?!
人造人間はどうだ
いいところへ来たな　グリード
Great timing, Greed.
親孝行な息子よ
You're such a good son.
ちょうど賢者の石が欲しかったところだ
I was just in need of a philosopher's stone.
もらい受けるぞ
I'll be taking yours.
なんつってなぁ
Just kidding.
防壁　外さなきゃ
You can't take my philosopher's stone without putting your barrier down, right?
賢者の石は奪えないよなぁ
だが　逆に自分が神の力とやらを
Did you not consider the possibility that you'd have the power of God taken from you instead?
奪われるとは思わなかったのか
オレがすべてもらい受ける
I'll take all of it!
グリード
Greed!
あきらめるな
Don't give up!
素手で…防御した
He... blocked it himself.
ヤツの限界だ
He's at his limit!
あいつはもう神とやらを
He can no longer hold down God!
抑え込んでいられない
石…石
Stone...!
Stone!
賢者の石
Philosopher's stone!
逃げろ　エドワード
Run, Edward!
兄さん　逃げて
Brother, run!
兄さん
Brother!!
やめろ　くっそ
Stop it!
Dammit!!
Sir Al!
アル様
やめろ…やめろ
Stop...!
Stop it!
兄さんを…兄さんを…
Help...
Help him...!
兄さんを…
Help my-
メイ　頼みがある
May, I need you to do me a favor.
兄さんは右腕を犠牲にして
Brother got my soul back by sacrificing his right arm.
僕の魂を戻してくれた
だったら　逆も可能なはず
In that case, it should be possible to do the opposite.
アルフォンス様…
Sir Alphonse...?
道を作ってくれるだけでいい
All I need you to do is to make a path.
できるだろ
You can do it, right?
そんなことしたら
But if I did that, you'd...!
アルフォンス様が
時間がない　お願いだ
We're running out of time!
Please.
こんなこと頼めるの　君しかいない
You're the only one I can ask to do something like this.
石…人間…
Stone...
Human...
エネルギー…
Energy...!
エドワード
Edward!!
よこせ
Give it to me!!
何をする気だ…
What are you trying to do...?
やめろ…
Cut it out...
Hey...
アル
Al!
勝てよ　兄さん
Win this, Brother.
やめろ
Don't do it!!!
もう　いいのかい
Was that enough for you?
Yeah.
あとは兄さんを信じる
All that's left for me to do now is to believe in him.
Yo. Looks like you got your soul back.
魂　入ったんだな
あいつはお前を取り戻しに来るか
Think he'll come here to bring you back?
来る　絶対に
He will. I know he will.
何を犠牲にするか楽しみだ
I'm curious to see what he'll sacrifice to do so.
バカ野郎っ
You idiot!!
効いてる
It's working.
いける　いけるぞ
He... He has a chance!
いけ
Keep it up!
小僧
Kiddo!!
いけ　いけ
That's the spirit!
やったれ　チビ助
Get him, kid!
突っ込め
Rush in!
エドワード君
Edward!
エド
Ed!
エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric!
いけぇ
Go!!
グリード
Greed.
お前が欲してやまなかったもの…
Isn't this...
本当はこれだろ
...what you've always wanted more than anything?
エドワードさん
Mr. Edward!
エドワード
Edward!
いけ
Go!
鋼の
Fullmetal!
Yeah, you're right on target.
そうだ
オレが欲しかったのは…
What I've always wanted...
こいつらみたいな
...are friends like these.
仲間だったんだな
Get up, punk!
立てよ　ど三流
オレたちとお前の
I'll show you the difference between us!
格の違いってやつを見せてやる
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
次回　鋼の錬金術師
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
His power could bring anything about.
Fullmetal　Alchemist
第６３話　『扉の向こう側』
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
However, he does not hesitate.
すべてを見届けて
Not when it is to protect the ones he loves.
その者は逝く
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 63, The Other Side of the Gateway.
He fades away after overseeing all.